Never forget why you are the church.
As we were singing, you know, Again,
I can't help to.
As we gathered together, turn your bowels around as 12, by the way, just to
get a head start, but as we're gathered together, and
We're in different walks of life and different phases of life, and
there's so much going on that a lot of us don't
even know about each other and our families and marriages, and our
health and everything that's going on.
I just, I got to thinking about how it would be easy for
someone to say, what do you mean?
You're never going to let me down?
I'm just being honest.
I mean, you know, I'm singing that and I'm thinking to myself, I
guarantee you there's people here that, like, why are we singing this?
Because I feel like I've been let down.
I want to encourage you this morning.
Even though you may have not got the answer you wanted.
Even though the circumstance you're in right now is not ideal.
Even though the situation that you have found yourself.
And may be painful and hurt and Confusing
and discouraging, I need you to know something.
We have a good, good father.
We have Yahweh Elohim.
The Redeemer Creator.
And he never lets us down.
Because he operates according to his will and his glory.
He's not taken by surprise.
He doesn't react in such a way that it's just a quick reaction.
No, no, no.
He is before the beginning.
He created you.
And yet he wants to know you.
Amen.
So no, he will never let you down.
Ooh, get back up here and say.
No, I'm just kidding.
We'll do that later.
All right, Romans chapter 12.
Y'all good this morning?
All right.
We're going to continue and I'll be honest with you.
I'm enjoying, um, this portion of text in Romans.
I, uh, we were talking uh, this weekend.
I was talking to some brothers and we were talking about
how, you know, it's fun to dig deep.
It's fun to go into all the speculations of what
is this and what is that?
And we do a little bit of that on Wednesday nights with Revelation.
But I, my heart and
my mind, it goes more towards the
applicable scripture of my everyday life.
In other words, God, what do you want from me right here, right now?
Does that make sense?
Like, God, what would you have me do here in this situation?
And so, because here's what I know.
I don't know exactly what is to come.
I know who is coming.
Y'all make fun of me doing this all the time.
Y'all should know what it means by now.
That means just say something, right?
We know who is coming.
That's Jesus.
He is going to return.
I did a funeral for Miss Cavenada.
I did her celebration of life on Monday.
And what I share with him.
First, that's on his chapter 4.
There's going to be a return.
There's going to be a resurrection, and there's going to be a reunion.
The Bible says that we'll be caught up together in the clouds with them,
those who have gone before us to be with Jesus forever.
Amen?
That's what I'm talking about there.
That is going to happen.
But what about right now?
What about the obedience and the faithfulness that
we are expected of, and we should, out of a
grateful heart of our salvation, and Lord
and Savior Jesus, we live in obedience.
If you love me, keep my commandments is what Jesus said.
So as we go through these one at a time, understand this is not just preacher talk.
This is not just a fun time on a Sunday morning.
No, this is how we're going to fight the battle on a daily basis,
not just alone, but together.
And so in Romans chapter 12.
It says this, and verse 14, it says we
already looked over this, but blessed sandwich persecutes you, blessed and cursed not.
When people persecute you.
That is a direct and personal attack on you.
That's not somebody giving you a dirty look.
That's not somebody not shaking your hand on a Sunday morning.
That's not somebody at work, you know, not adding you
in on an email about a little party going on, something.
That's not
no, no, no.
We need to know what persecution really is.
It is a direct attack based on your faith.
Listen, if you feel like your life is going wrong and you're living
in sin, that's not persecution, that's your sin.
You need to get that right.
You need to get rid of that.
You need to repent of it.
And so bless them, which persecutes you, blessed and curse not.
And then we looked again, it was last week, I think it was.
Maybe verse 14 was 2 weeks.
I don't know.
We've been in this study for like 14 years.
I'm not sure where we are.
Amen?
Romans 12 verse 15, rejoice within it.
Do rejoice and weep with them that weep.
When you see someone on their best day, how do you respond?
It is so easy.
And if we're honest, we agree.
It's so easy to ignore, neglect,
and to talk down upon someone doing good in life.
Out of jealousy, out of pride, out of ego, we
hear something that's going on good, or we hear they get this,
promotion, and we hear they get that or whatever it is, and all
of a sudden, we get so ingrained the fact that,
well, why this, why that?
Listen, we need to rejoice with those who rejoice.
I want to be able to rejoice with pastors who are seeing their
church grow exponentially.
I want to be able to weep with pastors that are going through a hard time in their church.
That's what I want to be like.
If my wife, Heather's having a great day.
Let's celebrate together.
And she's having a bad day.
Let's cry together.
You understand what I'm saying here this morning?
We've got to be willing to rejoice when something
good happens with our brother and sister in Christ, but also willing
to weep with them through a tough time.
You know that works both ways, though.
I can't weep with you if you don't if
you don't invite me in to the weeping session.
A lot of people say, well, I'm good, don't worry about me.
Well, I, I, you know, yeah, I'm struggling and and
and things, you know, my life is falling apart.
I don't know what way to turn, but, you know, just don't worry about it.
Well, I'm already concerned.
Amen?
You know why?
Because I love you.
It's just as simple as that.
We were commanded to walk with each other through the good and the bad.
And this brings us to the next command that we're gonna talk about in Romans 12, verse 16.
If you there, say, read.
That wasn't that good.
Let's try it again.
If you're there to say, read.
That was better.
It says this, be the same mind, one toward another.
Mind not high things, but condescends to men of low estate.
Be not wise in your own conceits.
See, we continue to look at the theme, the impact of the gospel in our relationships,
and the title for this morning goes along with the previous 2
messages of the last 2 weeks.
We're looking at the power of humility.
The power, of humility.
Let's pray.
Father, we thank you, Lord.
Now we thank you, that you sent Jesus to this earth, and he
was the meek Messiah.
Had all the power of the entire universe, yet, he
came as a lowly servant.
So God, I pray that we have that heart posture towards others as well.
May this not just be another message and another Sunday gathering that we go
and check it out the list, but God I pray, Lord, you speak to us this morning.
God, if someone here is lost when I pray today,
They call upon your name.
In Jesus name, prayer, but he said,
Amen.
For clarity's sake, I wanna look at this verse in the NSB 95 for
a clearer view of it, just an easier read on it.
Be of the same mind toward one another.
Do not be haughty in mind, but associate with the lowly.
Do not be wise in your own estimation.
Now, there are 3 parts of this command that we're going to look at.
In reality, this command speaks both on our responses
and actions towards each other, both
lost and saved.
The 1st part speaks on the necessity of unity.
Look what it says.
It says, be of the same mind toward one another.
Again, this connects with verse 15 and verse 16.
You cannot be, uh, you cannot be humble without having a statement.
You cannot rejoice with someone who's rejoicing and weeping with
someone who is weeping if you don't have the same mind with one another.
You cannot have empathy for someone unless there is
an attitude and heart posture of unity towards them.
And at the same time, you cannot be walking in
obedience as well.
So what does it mean to be of the same mind?
Well, it means to think the same.
Now, that right there is difficult.
Amen?
I was raised differently than a lot of y'all.
Y'all are raised different than me.
We come from different upbringings, different, this, different, that.
We have a lot of different thoughts about a lot of different things, do we not?
As a matter of fact, you might be thinking right now, well,
that is impossible.
There's no way I can think like that person over there.
And listen, that's what we that's what we say a lot.
And we may not be a large church, but if you don't think
that we have a vast and diverse congregation, you are not talking to
your fellow Cedar Grovians enough.
The more you get to know each other, what you're going to learn is, man, we're different.
So, for example, we have some who are crunchy.
Right?
They no red dye, no no preservatives,
nothing like that, you know what I'm saying?
Like, don't you dare, feed us, any kind of,
you know, church.
By the way, we've been feeding kids, those little whales at church for
since Tower of Babble.
understand?
When the adults were building a building, they were eating the little whales, all right?
Okay?
I don't know what they got in them now, but they're good, okay?
But either way, we got those that are crunchy.
We have some that couldn't care anything about that.
Red dye, cool.
Like, listen, I mean, we got we got a vast amount of differences here.
We have people that shop organic and others who shop generic.
Listen, I shop at Sprouts one time.
I'm still recovering.
Listen, dude, I was trying to do some, some, uh, summer prep.
I'm just in sprouts, studying the Bible.
No, I was trying to do some meal prepping doing some chicken,
trying to eat as much protein as what I weigh.
When you wait like I do.
That's a lot of food, amen?
And I bought that chicken.
read, don't you don't you agree so hard on that buddy?
I saw that.
Yeah.
This ain't that big of a church.
Anyway, so but listen, so I went in there and man, I bought all kind of chicken.
It was that chicken and it had been frozen.
You know what I'm saying?
It's good stuff.
It's awesome.
So man, I bought it.
And listen, the chicken was on the bottom because that was the 1st section we went to.
By the time we got to the chicken, we were $300 in.
And I'm sitting here holding my cheek when
my wallet was like, what is going?
We put it on.
It was like 400 and $80 or something like that.
And I told Heather, I said,
I hope you enjoyed this, because this is legitimately our last supper, right, man?
There's no way in the world.
And if you go to Sprouts, praise the Lord.
I hope you tithe.
Anyway, so.
We have Walmart people, and we have Publix people.
We have listen, we have Trumpers and never Trumpers.
Now, the crazy thing about that is some of y'all just got really mad about that.
We have differences.
Hey, man.
We have some who grew up Baptists.
We have some who grew up Catholic and other Pentecostals and other
Church of Christ.
We have some people who have kids and others who do not.
We have some who spank and some who count the five.
Amen?
And we got encounters in the room.
My auntie used to count and I couldn't stay.
That's one.
By the time something actually happened, it was like 147 counts, you understand what I'm saying?
Whoop, whoop.
But anyway, we have some who have been married since they were a teenager, and we
have some who have experienced the pain of divorce.
We have some who are married and some who are single.
We have some with childhood trauma and some with not
very much childhood trauma.
We have some that homeschool and some that send their kids to public school.
You have some who like hymns and some who like contemporary.
We have some who wish the peers would return.
And we have some who think that we should have gone to chairs years ago.
We have some who think that the light should be
on during worship, and we have some that, man, hey, black it
out, and I like it when no one can see in worship.
We have some who read KJV and some that read NIV or ESV.
We have some who are just making it by financially and others who have plenty.
We have some who think eating out is a waste of money and others
who enjoy chili's.
That's me.
Chills and demons, man.
good.
We have Tennessee Balls fans, and then we have others.
Bunch of weirdos.
We've got pro sport people.
We got college sport people.
We got firefighters and we got policemen.
Evidently, that's a thing.
We have nine owls, and we have early rhymes.
We have procrastinators and we have early preparers.
We have introverts, we have extroverts.
We have people who have been saved since the flood, and others who are babes in Christ.
We have, we listen, church, we have people that clap on one and three.
And we got those that clap correctly on 2 and 4.
Guys, we got differences.
We got those who speak Spanish?
Sorry.
I heard Carlos, amen.
I was like, oh, I gotta say something.
Oh, Aspi, yes, we got some.
I said some, not just one.
Cedar grows diverse.
Ooh, I need a hanky.
All right.
But again, if you think we all have oh, brother.
Gracias.
That's all I know.
end the conversation.
But if you think we all have the same perspective, you're not paying attention.
You're tragically mistaken.
However, God's command is the same.
You don't think God knows our differences?
You don't think God has brought us together for a reason?
Look again, be of the same mind toward one another.
I can tell you one thing for sure.
We all think the way we view things is right.
If you come to me and you have a different opinion, I'm gonna, you
know, you're wrong.
But the way we choose to live our life, right?
we think, well, the way I do things, it's right, and
if you don't do it this way, I won't really tell you, but I just,
in my mind, my heart posture, I just know you're wrong.
I think that you're wrong.
I think you're incorrect.
You not doing things.
Like you should.
As a matter of fact, we might even slightly look down upon those who don't
see things the way we see them.
Church, the devil has done a great job in dividing us.
How in the world can we take all these differences and be at the same mind?
How can we think the same?
And we obviously do not think the same.
Well, the answer is found to the question here.
Why are we together?
What is the purpose of the church?
Our purpose is stated clearly in our mission statement.
I've already told you, but it starts with loving others unconditionally.
That means in the condition they're in.
Guess what?
their condition might be different than your condition.
We gotta love them anyway.
We cannot expect to learn about God increasingly.
You live to share Jesus intentionally or lead others to Christ continually
unless we get that 1st part of love, right?
But is this purpose that reveals why we are here.
Before every video that we post on YouTube or on
our media player, there is an intro that is aligned, I said, in a certain,
I mean, I don't know how long ago, but a long, long time ago.
But this is what it says very simply.
Never forget why you are the church.
I feel like sometimes we forget that.
We turn it into something that we go to.
We turned it into an event.
We are here, church, for the glory of God.
We are here to celebrate the life, the death, and the resurrection of Jesus Christ.
We are here to learn of the way, the truth, and the life.
We do not have to think the same on everything, but we must think the
same about Jesus.
And if we think the same about Jesus, God can work through our differences.
And what the enemy could attempt to work for evil.
God goes ahead and turns that for good.
See, the enemy will try to amplify differences to get us arguing with each other.
While God in scripture tells us your differences is my plan.
and my purpose for the church.
Guys, if everybody planned an event like I planned the event here, we'd have no money.
Because I spend it all.
We'd have every inflatable in Middle Tennessee.
Understand what I'm saying?
Adelita's ice cream, here.
As a matter of fact, we got him on retainer, you understand?
Like, but we have people that are have different gifts,
have different perspectives, and it all works together for the glory of God.
This command is one that has echoed throughout the New Testament.
Paul and his farewell in 2nd Corinthians 13, 11.
Think about it.
He basically whoops the church in Corinth.
I'm talking about like, they got that letter and he's like, listen, hey, you got some stuff to work on.
You, you, you know, you need to, you need to do this.
you need to do that.
You need to get together.
But what he says in verse 11.
Finally, brethren, rejoice, be made complete, be comforted,
be like-minded, live in peace, and
the God of love and peace will be with you.
We have to be like minded.
Think the same about the things that matter.
We know there are so many tensions and conflicts that come up in the local church.
Why do you think that is?
You want to know why the church seems to never have peace for long?
You know what?
Do you know what the most probably frequent
saying in a thriving church is?
Hey, just be careful when things start to go good.
something's going to go bad.
Listen, what that is, is tension, that's conflict.
That's a different, that's a difference in opinion about things that are happening.
That doesn't have to happen.
We, we can, we can think the same on magnifying
the ministry here at Cedar Grove Baptist Church.
We don't have to think the same on every little detail of
how, but guess what?
We are bought into the vision.
We are committed to Christ here.
We can have peace.
There are those who refuse to be like-minded.
It is their way or no way.
You know, I tried that.
And God humbled me.
We see this command to the church in Philippi, Philippians 2,
verse two, make my joy complete by being of the same mind.
Maintaining the same love, united
in spirit, intent on one purpose.
Why did you come here this morning?
There's really only one purpose in it.
That's to glorify the Lord.
Everything else we can hash out.
But we're here for his glory.
Again, in Philippians in 2 chapters later, we see Paul
call out 2 women who were in an obvious, intense conflict.
Imagine that in a Baptist church, amen?
Did I just get in trouble there?
I'm sorry.
Why'd y'all get so quiet?
ladies, laugh at that joke.
It was about you.
Anyway.
But it was affecting the entire congregation.
Look, look at Paul says.
I beseech Eudius, and I beseech Sentite,
did they be of the same mind in the Lord?
I studied that.
I don't have time to go into it, but there was an obvious tension
in the fact that it was literally affecting the entire
body of Christ.
Their argument was.
Paul was like, stop it.
Be of one mind.
You're here for one purpose.
If you don't think personal quarrels and vendettas hurt the church, you lack
both common sense and self-awareness.
And it may be that you're the one that's making them.
Or worse, you don't care as long as you get your way.
Again, I've been there.
We were in the budget committee.
I was saying, hey, I want a $10000 budget.
We only brought in like 300, but I want to go to a million.
They're like, no.
I was like, okay.
Why?
Because they think differently than I do.
Now I'm exaggerated.
Philip's like, Don't say these things.
But you know what?
We're steward and God's, the one purpose of that committee was a
steward, the blessing well.
And I believe we did it.
When Peter wrote to the believers who were scattered abroad, he told them, finally,
be in 1st Peter 38, finally, be ye of all of
one mind, having compassion, one of another, love his brethren,
be pitiful, be courteous.
We must stay focused on what keeps us together.
His name is Jesus.
We are on the same mission.
We have differing differing gifts for the same work of the ministry.
We cannot let the enemy have a stronghold.
And so that brings us to the 2nd part is command, look at verse 16.
Again, it says, be of the same mind toward one another, but then it says, do not be
haughty in mind, but associate with the lowly.
That word haughty means something very simple means to be arrogant.
Now, we think of arrogance is something that meant,
surely people aren't arrogant to church.
Let me just tell you something.
When you serve in a church long enough, people think they know better than anybody else.
And if you're not careful, you'll be the same.
Now, we've already read about this in Romans 12, verse 11,
for through the grace given to me, I say to everyone among you
not to think more highly of himself than he ought to think.
But to think so as to have sound judgment as God has
allotted to each measure of faith.
Guys, listen, even walking in, right?
This morning, we had a family, they needed to check in.
I don't know about no check in.
I know y'all talk about it a whole lot in the meetings, right?
Is he working?
Is it this, is this, isn't it?
And so they were like, they came to me.
They were like, hey, can you help us check in?
I'm like, sure can't.
But I can find someone who can.
You don't think I'd like to solve that problem myself?
Now, I could have sat there with the iPad and tried to figure it out and
do this and do that, or I could just go get someone who knew what they were doing.
We got to walk in humility with this.
Who are you better than?
This is a question if you have the audacity to answer, honestly, out loud.
But our actions answer it louder than any word could.
Who are you better than?
You hear me this morning, just because someone has, uh, with sins
differently than you do, does not make you better than them.
I grew up in a system that was
somewhat very legalistic when it comes to, if you do this, your,
your, your, 2nd class.
If you do that, you're second, this happening.
And when you just start loving on people, you realize, man, life happens sometimes.
And as I walk with my people through these hard times, you know what it does?
It encourages me to stay the course.
Not in an arrogant way, but in a way of like, hey, you
know, we want this unity.
I don't I don't want to make the mistakes that others have made.
Show me how not to.
I'm one of the I'm one of the longest tenured pastors in this
area, believe it or not.
And I remind my pastor friends constantly.
So how long you been there?
Three years?
Oh, that's cute.
Ask you, you're still in the honeymoon stage.
Don't be arrogant.
Anyway.
But you know what's crazy?
We have a group message.
I'm the one who asked the most questions.
Because I've learned that I've got a lot to learn.
Now, I'm not, listen, I'm not saying that I'm self righteous, got it going on,
but we have to understand it.
We're not better than others.
Jesus Christ, God in the flesh in his short ministry here on Earth.
He could be found more with the castaways and sinners than with the religious crowd.
And by the way, for you that says, oh, well, you can just find me in the
bar, find me in the club then, because Jesus hung out there, Jesus
was on mission, why are you there?
We can be so dumb sometimes.
I'm gonna go, I'm gonna go and get drunk at the bar, because Jesus went to...
No, stop it.
Be on mission.
And you'll find yourselves outside of those situations because you realize,
hey, I don't need those temptations.
But what you do is you seek after those who are lost in any way you can.
And we're sitting here thinking that we have the strength of Christ.
We have Christ, but we better be humble.
But again, as a matter of fact, he was with when he was with
the scribes and Pharisees, he was primarily rebuking them.
Luke Vibers 27 through 31.
After that, he went out and noticed a tax collector named Levi sitting in
the tax booth, and he said to him, follow me.
Y'all like taxes?
Neither did they in this time.
No one has ever in the history of the world.
like taxes.
And he left everything behind and got up and began to follow him.
And Levi gave a big reception for him in his house, and
there was a great crowd of tax collectors and other
people who were reclining at the table with them.
Be like walking in a room and half the IRS is in there.
What you gonna do?
Walk out.
But Jesus was there.
The Pharisees and the scribes began grumbling at his disciples
saying, why do you eat and drink with the tax
collectors and sinners?
And Jesus answered him.
It is not those who are well who need a physician, but those who are sick.
He was on mission.
Are you too good for soul winning?
Proverbs 11, verse 30.
The fruit of the righteous is a tree of life, and he who wins, he
who is wise wins souls.
You know, the wisest thing we can do on this earth.
is share the gospel.
This phrase to associate with a lowly can also mean to accommodate
yourself to lowly things.
Lowly, undistinguished, common in the New Testament,
generally refers to being in a low position socially or to be humble.
Some of you know that I, I went to, um,
We, well, some of us here have gone to Honduras several times in
the past and I think the last time we went as a church
family was in 2018, I believe, is that right, Amber, 2018?
And, um,
And and man, going with Amber's dad, who's with the Lord
now, but, um, one of the great missionaries I've
ever met in my life because he would do that other missionaries wouldn't do.
See, a lot of missionaries that I go with, there's a schedule and if if
it's not on the schedule, we're not doing it.
I kind of like sporadic ministry sometimes.
That's why I need people to, you know, hold me in and make sure
they don't do crazy things, but We were going and there
was a young man named Josue.
This young man, I think at that time, 16, was he 16 or something like that?
I remember the last time we went to Honduras with another mission group,
and listen, I'm not saying anything bad.
I'm just, I'm complimenting the way that Brother Tim did things.
We didn't have time to go see Josue.
It's a big walk.
It's a big drive.
See, Ho Sway, if I'm not mistaken, he was very special needs.
Was he dropped or something?
Is that what happened?
I think something happened to where he had to lay on the ground.
He couldn't function.
He would eat cornflakes and powdered milk.
That was his life.
His dad was really, really old.
His sister had been tragically abused at a young age.
So she was mute.
You'd walk in, and there was just a...
There was a stench.
But you know what I loved about it is this.
We got to associate with the lowly.
Because they need encouragement too.
And so I think we asked your dad, we said, hey, can we go see Josue?
You've seen him a time or 2 before he trips and he's like, yep.
We'll just eat dinner later.
So we went in St.
Jose way.
We walked in there.
And the scene was just.
It was hard.
We brought him some gifts, I think, because we were going to see him anyway, but we didn't
know when, and we brought a sword, and, and I'll
never forget, we gave him, like, this little foam sword, and he'd take the sword, and he'd
hit me, and I'd fall on the ground.
I didn't care what was on the ground.
I didn't associate in lovely things.
I got down on the ground with him.
Like this, right?
Because he's laying on a cot.
I mean, literally he's just laying on the floor.
Got down on the ground with them, like this right here, and I started singing, How great is our God with them?
And he was just grinning ear to ear.
He couldn't say the words, but he knew the words.
Guys, listen, I know that seems intense, by the way, and he's on my heart.
He was on my mind because I don't know if you saw on Facebook, but He
went to be with the Lord this past week.
Imagine if I refused.
Uh, doesn't smell good in there.
Ah, it makes me uncomfortable.
I don't I don't like to see people in that state.
Ah, he won't remember me anyway.
I let everyone else go in.
It's just too much for me.
No, God allowed me to minister.
Toe sway.
And I'll never get to again until I see him in heaven.
And guess what?
He's not gonna be laying on no ground.
He might have that foam sword with him.
And give me a real good fight, amen?
But all I'm trying to say is this.
Hey, listen.
We're no better.
Now with me this morning.
If Jesus was not too good for this, I can assure you of one thing, neither are you or I.
James gives a scorching description.
We almost done here of this in James chapter 2, verse one and nine, one through nine.
My brethren, do not hold your faith in our glorious Lord Jesus Christ with an attitude
of personal favoritism.
For if a man comes into your assembly with a gold ring and dressed in fine
clothes, and there also comes in a poor man in dirty clothes, and
you pay special attention to the one who is wearing a fine clothes and
say, hey, you sit here in a good place, and you say to the poor man, you stand
over there or sit down by my footstool.
Have you not made distinctions among yourself and become
judges with evil motives?
Listen, my beloved brethren.
Did not God choose the poor this world to be rich in faith and heirs
of the kingdom, which he promised to those who love him?
But you have dishonored the poor man.
It is not the rich who oppress you.
Is it not the rich who oppress you and personally drag you into court?
They're not blaspheming the fair name by which you have been called.
If, however, you are fulfilling a royal law, according to scripture, you
shall love your neighbor as yourself, you are doing well.
But if you show partiality, you are committing sin and are convicted
by the law as transgressors.
You know, sometime, and I just, I'm just being transparent with you.
Sometimes I feel like, man, I wish we had like some, some, you
know, crazy, like, mob top billionaires to come in here and do all this.
I feel like every other church is like, yes, somebody just stroked the $500,000 check.
We build a building, you know what I'm saying?
Listen, I'd rather have someone that loves the Lord that works nursery,
that teaches our kids, that greets people at the door, that may not be able to
give much, but they're giving themselves.
I take that all day every day.
Why?
Because listen, there's no partiality.
God can use little and do much with it.
And so we got to understand it.
We have to minister in the same way.
So we come to the 3rd part of this command.
If you're still with me, say amen.
Romans 1216, be the same mind toward one another.
Do not be haughty in mind, but associate with the lowly.
Do not be wise in your own estimation.
Are you the smartest person you know?
When other people speak, do you instantly have a better way?
Man, that sounds real good, except, you know, that's dumb.
Like people, that's how people interact with each other.
Church, it's not that we don't strive for excellence.
But what we do is we strive for excellence together.
Proverbs 37, it says, do not be wise in your own eyes, fear
the Lord and turn away from evil.
How many people have been hindered or have hindered unity because they
can't, they have came in with a self-conceited mindset.
Listen, I want this church.
I want this flock to be lifted up in the side of God, and there's only one
way to do that scripturally.
James 410, humble yourselves in the side of the Lord, and he shall lift you up.
As we close with the 12 disciples, within the 12 disciples that Jesus called in
the gospels, you had a lot of ordinary man.
Some were fishermen, one was a tax collector.
There was even a revolutionary in a group, a really, uh,
political zealot.
There were some that were uneducated, there were some that educated.
There was some that had money, didn't have money.
But yet these 12 men all had one mission.
These 12 men were following one person.
Jesus used these 12 ordinary men with all different walks
of life to bring the gospel to the entire world.
We are a product and result of these
men following Christ.
But there was one.
His name was Judas.
Judas was not like-minded with the others.
He didn't think the same.
His mind was set on material things, and he
got offended when they would use money for things he
didn't deem was correct.
And as a matter of fact, when the woman came and poured that expensive perfume
upon Jesus and kissed
his feet and washed his feet with her hair and all the things.
Listen, he sat there and he thought, man, this is disgusting.
We could have sold this and done so much good with it.
And Jesus basically said, you've got the wrong mindset.
What is the point here?
Judas is the one that eventually betrayed Christ.
We were all here for one purpose serving the Lord.
May nothing else getting aware of that purpose.
Be of the same mind toward one another.
Do not be haughty in mind, but associate with a lowly.
Do not be wise in your own estimation.
Church, we on mission together.
Do we think the same about Jesus?
Do we think the same?
About ministry.
The goal, the purpose of it.
We don't have to all like contemporary music.
We don't have to all like the hymns.
We don't all have to like the chairs in the pews.
We don't have to all like the fact that there's tape in the fellowship hall.
It's like, what does this tape about kids are going to play in there?
That's that's a purpose that we have unified, is that we are trying to
teach the kids of our church the gospel.
So guess what?
We got some tape in the fellowship, Paul.
You understand what I'm saying?
We got to think the same.
Somebody walks in and they look a little bit different than we do.
They don't have as nice clothes as we got.
Maybe they walk different.
Maybe they think different.
Maybe whatever it is.
Listen, hey, we as a church got to think the same.
God loves them too.
Are we on the same mission?
It has been eyes closed off at this place.